Wilson Ler

 ♥ San Francisco, California, United States
 ■ lws803@gmail.com
 □ (226) 280-2518
 ■ in/wilsonler
 ♥ github.com/lws803

SUMMARY

Technical Co-founder of Beloga, building a thinking and functioning AI second brain for knowledge-intensive tasks. Experienced in natural language processing (NLP), retrieval-augmented generation (RAG), and full-stack development. Former Engineering Manager at Constructor with a track record of leading successful teams and delivering impactful projects.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder

Beloga

February 2024 - Present, San Francisco Bay Area

- · Built an MVP in 6 months and launched 2nd Product of the day on Product Hunt.
- · Lead product development and technical architecture from 0 to 1.
- · Scaled revenue from \$0 \$3K MRR and 400 MAUs.
- Built the platform using multi-source RAG with personalization.
- · Achieved 3 hours of engagement time per day per user.

Technical Consultant

Break Sports

June 2024 - August 2024, New York (Remote)

- · Assisted in restructuring of engineering team and hiring 4 new engineers.
- Led architectural decisions to resolve up to 20% of technical debt.
- · Provided technical leadership and strategic guidance.

Engineering Manager

Constructor

August 2021 - February 2024, Remote

- · Founded and led a team of full-stack engineers to build a quiz platform for e-commerce guided experiences.
- · Streamlined hiring pipeline with new processes and buddy system, reducing onboarding time by 30%.
- · Led development of customer merchandizing tools that increased clickthrough rates.
- · Implemented OpenAPI auto-documentation generation, eliminating manual documentation needs.
- · Developed Sentry auto-assignment bot improving error handling coverage by 80%.

Software Engineer

Constructor

August 2019 - August 2021, Remote

- Scaled Constructor from a valuation of \$50M to \$550M as an early engineer.
- Revamped API documentation site to increase engagement by 50%.
- · Developed configuration interfaces for customer catalog data.
- Refreshed and refactored analytics dashboard to improve user experience.
- Implemented dynamic synonyms to replace static lists.
- · Optimized redirect rules reducing indexing time by 50%.
- Developed time-based searchandizing rules with conflict resolution.
- · Added multilingual search detection for French, Dutch, and English.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Minor in NUS Overseas Colleges (Entrepreneurship) \cdot National University of Singapore \cdot Singapore \cdot 2017 — 2021

- · Honors Graduate.
- · Focus areas: Information Retrieval, Natural Language Processing (NLP).

Visiting Student

Stanford University · Palo Alto, California · 2019

- · Completed CS229 Machine Learning course.
- Part of NUS Overseas Colleges Silicon Valley program (Batch 36).

PROJECTS

GigaChadGPT

github.com/lws803/gigachadgpt · December 2023 - December 2023

- Developed a ChatGPT-based persona through prompt engineering.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Created an engaging conversational AI for fitness and lifestyle advice.
- · Achieved 50+ DAUs on the platform.

Bluetooth Low Energy Jammer

github.com/lws803/BLE-jammer · December 2022 - December 2022

- Built a Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) jammer using NRF240L+ modules and Maple Mini (STM32).
- \cdot Achieved 170 stars on GitHub.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Was able to jam up to 100m of BLE communications.

SKILLS

Technologies: Large Language Models (LLM), Retrieval-Augemented Generation (RAG), React.js, NestJS, JavaScript, Information Retrieval Soft Skills: Leadership, Hiring, Project Management, Building an Engineering Culture